this is the third leg of the sub Club
podcast World Tour so we've been in
London and Vegas we're going to be with
app promotion Summit in San Francisco
and Berlin later this year talking with
experts in the subscription app space
and today super excited to have Stephen
from Babel so let's get going tell me a
little bit about your role at Babel and
what Babel is Babel's a language
learning subscription platform we're
best known probably for our app but we
do live classes podcasts games you can
find all of that stuff in our app we've
been around since pretty early on 2007
so we actually predate the IOS app store
but uh yeah we've had a successful run
over the years cool so what I was super
excited to talk to you about today is
offline ads like everybody in the app
industry is how do I make meta work you
know apps search ads one of the things
I've talked to so many people on the
podcast about and kind of been beating
the drum for a while now is like
marketing is marketing like find
creative ways to find those top personas
that people are going to spend in your
app but so few people Venture Beyond
those kind of like standard practices
and know Babel is kind of a master at
just trying whatever works so first off
tell me like what's the philosophy
behind the expansive marketing that
Babble does yeah I mean I think it
starts there where we're open to
anything that works and it's kind of
interesting like where generally known
as an app but I think we've really made
our name on the offline marketing side
of things and a little bit the reason
behind that is like we don't really view
ourselves as just being an app so we
don't behold ourselves to the
traditional app marketing channels like
our users are everywhere and so we feel
like our marketing should be everywhere
and I think we found pretty early on as
we were experimenting with different
marketing channels that we had struck a
on some offline channels and we're
talking traditional TV radio Podcast you
know and I think there weren't a lot of
our our competition wasn't really there
yeah so we kind of were able to carve
out a little space for ourselves one of
the things you told me that really
struck me is that you know too many apps
think of themselves as just an app but
really you're providing a service to
users and people don't think of you just
as an app they think of you as like I
want to learn a language and like yes
one of the ways facilitate that it's
through the app but like you're just
providing a service in their life and
thinking about your business more
broadly in that way helps you then think
about Marketing in a more broad way yeah
yeah absolutely and I think probably
most subscription companies even if you
have just an app are hopefully trying to
do a little bit more than just get a
download and you know that's a little
bit of the way we we think about it is
we have metrics much beyond the download
and for offline channels since we're
we're talking about that it's a little
bit of a different audience than you
might get on some of your traditional
app-based marketing channels the
audience tends to skew a little bit
older they actually tend to be a little
bit non-technical when you're talking
linear TV radio and for us it worked
really well these people are usually
High income and they buy so it's a
little bit of a different audience um if
you're trying to monetize a subscription
app it works pretty well so it's always
surprising me that a lot of apps kind of
ignore this category of things yeah we
talk about that a l on podcast that for
a lot of apps they really struggle to
monetize in that under 30 age so if you
know that about your app like we're
struggling to monetize those younger
users those are easier to find on
Snapchat and Tik Tok and stuff like that
but if your high monetization users are
older there's so many channels to meet
them at and so one of the cool things
yall do is is a ton of radio spots what
does that look like advertising on radio
like are there minimum buys like what
would an app thinking okay I talked to
an app yesterday they know their
audience is like is moms in the
Midwest and that's probably a good like
buy a spot when you know moms are going
to be in the car dropping the kids off
at school or picking up the kids from
school like looking for opportunities
like that how would an app go about that
or the minimum spans how do you approach
radio as a channel so you just started
with probably the hardest CH that you
could have when it comes to offline
marketing so as far as targeting on
radio much more difficult to do you have
a few options when it comes to radio you
can do kind of direct host specific buys
where you contact a host and you get
them to do a very personalized read for
you and generally if you do it that way
you are going to hone in on a particular
audience the type of people that listen
to that particular host the downside of
that is it comes at a much higher cost
so the way we tend to buy radio is
pretty broad we buy it nationally and we
kind of scatter the entire country and
it comes at a much much cheaper cost so
as far as targeting you kind of have to
balance the idea of like am I willing to
pay more for a highly targeted audience
right or am I willing to go a little bit
broader and kind of get power of numbers
that way um so we tend to go the ladder
where we're buying much much broader our
audience is quite Broad and I think if
you feel like you have a pretty broad
audience like an offline channel is a
pretty good option for you in in that
regard is um and that's where the
efficiencies get is when you can buy a
little bit broader and not as expensive
like it's it's actually pretty
surprising I think most people would
view offline channels as the more
expensive channels to go after and when
you buy a certain way you can actually
achieve cpms that are probably much much
cheaper than uh Facebook for example
right and then linear TV another thing
you'll experiment with a lot what does
that look like yeah I mean linear is a
little bit different for those that
don't know linear that's your
traditional cable TV Watchers but you
know what's interesting about TV is it
is highly measurable at least a lot more
than it used to be it's not the same
type of measurement as you might have
with a traditional digital channel and
I'm sure we can into that topic at some
point in terms of how you measure all
this stuff but it is pretty similar how
we're buying TV it's pretty broad it's
the cheaper cpms we're buying a ton of
spots at very very low costs um and it
plays out really well for us yeah what
are some of the other crazy things
Billboards or direct mail or any other
crazy things you've experimented with
that you think app should try like it's
worth an experiment yeah I mean I've
done it all we've found a really good
place with linear TV radio and podcast
the other places you can go there's out
of home so if you're talking Billboards
Subway ads that kind of thing you can
also go direct mail in my experience
like those things tend to be more costly
and have much lower reach they work
pretty well if you're a GEOS specific
type of business where it's like I need
to only target people in a particular G
right so I found that like it gets
pretty inefficient for companies that
are just more broad it doesn't matter
where you are you're much better off
sticking into yeah like those larger
scale channels like TV and radio and
podcast so I think the the next question
everybody would be asking and you kind
of alluded to it already is I think the
scariest part for an app marketer
thinking about offline ads is how do I
measure and like how do I know this is
actually going to be effective so what
are your kind of top strategies for
understanding the effectiveness of this
yeah so I mean I can give a quick
rundown of how we're measuring it and I
will say like we're not Big Brand
marketers like we're not coming at this
like just throwing money at the wall we
don't care how it performs you know
we're trying to grow our brand you know
which is how most people probably view
the offline marketing channels in this
day and age I don't think it's like that
I think a lot of startups a lot of app
based business
that are doing this like they're looking
at it pretty similarly to how they
measure digital we go about it in a
different way so for digital you're
generally you know measuring an ad click
and offline we're leveraging how did you
hear responses it's just another data
point that we get to better tell the
story of what is happening and wh
everyone's coming from and so that's a
super effective way to understand how
the offline channels are working we kind
of combine all of these elements we have
click-based things coming in we have a
whole bunch of people that are coming
into our site or our app organically and
some of those people are saying that
they heard about us through TV or radio
and that's a way that we get to fill in
the blanks so it helps to like have that
extra data point and I'm not quite sure
you can really do offline marketing if
you're not if you're not open to like
collecting that information I mean
there's a ton of ambiguity in
measurement anyway and now it's probably
a good time to like Embrace that
ambiguity because you're not getting the
kind of signals you used to with the
idfa and Google's making big changes and
everything else like that so babbles had
to be had to embrace that ambiguity for
years and probably came into this postat
world a little more prepared so what are
some of the specific I know like with TV
you could potentially do some temporal
like you know when the ad drops do you
look at those kind of signals
media mix modeling incrementality those
kind of things so what's the mix of like
how you try and model what is actually
working the reality is even before all
of the new regulations and data privacy
laws attribution was always messy
despite what people think there's no
perfect solution and there actually
probably never never will be so we never
really changed our
model after those events there was
always a number of different signals
that we look for and that's I think the
number one thing to think about is that
you can't just rely on one source of
data or one model so we combine a number
of different things just to get closer
to reality that's all we're really
trying to do is we're trying to get
slightly better than having nothing so
we are looking at again web clicks and
where they're coming from like your
traditional digital marketing
attribution we do run incrementality
tests we do have some mmm models we are
looking at the how did you hear
responses that all of our users are
telling us where they came from and then
for channels like TV you can look at
what's called Spike attribution where
you actually look at when all of your
spots your TV spots ran and how much
that drove up traffic or downloads to
your website and you can actually
measure the incrementality on that for
every single TV spot that you run so you
can start optimizing for different
channels and different different
networks and different times a day a lot
of the same things that you would do
with digital marketing channels so yeah
when it comes to attribution I think the
number one thing is look at different
models and different sources of data and
try to find the best truth within that
right what does that look like on the
back end as far as like MMP and data
modeling like how how do you make sense
of it on a tactical level yeah I mean
you do need some level of data
sophistication but there are a lot of
platforms out there that help you you
know we have at Babel we have both you
know an app and a website so we're
getting web traffic you could use Google
analytics to track you know web events
we use adjust on the mobile side and all
this stuff comes with click data
attribution data campaign data
everything associated with that and yeah
we aggregate all that data together we
do have a wonderful data team that will
help make sense of a lot of this you
know we've come up with kind of a
proprietary model that we feel like is
the closest closest thing but yeah I
mean one of the hardest parts is
bringing all the data together the
fortunate thing is yeah there's a bunch
of tools out there that can help you do
that yeah and then for apps that you
know don't have a whole data team and a
sophisticated model looking at Blended
stats can be a really powerful thing
like how much should we spend last week
and then track that cohort over time and
you as you grow you can become more and
more sophisticated but but you can see
in the data like how much should we
spend that week and then how did that
cohort perform and and the model doesn't
have to be always be super sophisticated
especially as you're ramping up spend
like as you're spending less you don't
have to be as sophisticated once you get
to the size of a babble spending quite a
bit of money on Advertising then you do
want to be more and more sophisticated
about it but you typically would have
the resources to do that yeah I mean I
think that it's a good point one of the
amazing things that Google brought to
the table when it you know it came about
is that it made advertising more
accessible you didn't need a massive
budget to get going but I have found
that offline is headed in that direction
a lot more over the last couple years
where it doesn't take a massive upfront
investment to get started you can start
small B Babel started small and our
model has gotone much much better over
the years so yeah you can really start
anywhere I think cool a couple other
things I want to talk to you about one
was this idea of customer centered
metric so Babble is a hard pay wall app
and as you and I have talked about that
being a hard pay wall kind of forces
different reality on the business so I
wanted to start with I thought you had
some really insightful ideas around kind
of things to watch out for for premium
like subscription is almost Anonymous at
this point with the premium model but
that comes with a lot of drawback so
what are some of the from from the
outside in and not everybody here in the
room will have the opportunity to like
switch your app to a hard pay wall and
that's maybe not the right answer for
most apps but understanding from the
other side of the table somebody who
does have a hard pay wall kind of
understanding some of the pitfalls that
you see in the premium model I think
could be really helpful for folks and
then for some folks maybe hard pay wall
is the right answer I think that's a
really interesting question and I I do
love this topic because we have gone the
non-traditional way of having a hard pay
wall we do offer a free lesson in our
app so you can experience it a little
bit but there's really not that much you
can do and there's a different way that
we've approached it but I will start off
by saying that like fremium is not the
only option for an app and it really
might not work for everyone you look at
a few companies that have done it really
well and you think that that applies for
all apps and I really don't think it
does and for me personally I don't know
if I've ever purchased an app through a
free experience that I wasn't already
going to purchase anyway so it's really
difficult to get someone in and help
them make a decision that they wouldn't
have otherwise done especially when you
just drop them into a product and into a
less optimized product this the
suboptimal version of what that product
is going to be maybe we can do met a
quick metaphor right now but like okay
we're at the app promotion Summit like
maybe you're deciding if you want to
come to this event is it worth it for
you you're an app developer you have a
new app and you want to learn about you
know the app Marketplace how would you
decide whether you want to come to the
app promotion Summit let's say you went
and you Googled you know app
promotion conferences and app Summit
came up you came to the website
they were like hey come on in for free
you can watch via video the last
conference that we had and like you sit
there and you go around and you maybe
like don't have you're watching you
can't hear that well you don't know
which talk to listen to and you kind of
just you're like okay that was cool I
didn't get much value out it that you
leave the first thing is like app
promotion has no way of understanding
why that didn't really work for that
experience I find that that's the
experience that a lot of people get with
freemium
the way that we've taken it with Babel
and I think with any sales
process what's kind of like the number
one thing that A salesperson or sales
advice that someone gives to other
salespeople it's focus on the Discovery
stage when you're selling something to
someone what does the customer need find
out what their needs are where their
gaps are and figure out how you can fill
them and that's the approach that we've
taken at Babel where instead of just
like dumping you into our product and
letting you figure it out we try to
discover as much as we possibly can up
front and that's through a registration
and sign up experience that asks you a
bunch of questions and tries to figure
out as much as we possibly can about you
up front and in that process we're able
to talk about ourselves and tell you how
we fit into what your needs are and by
the time you get to the end of that
experience you feel already compelled to
buy you don't need to actually test the
app on your own so that's the approach
we've taken and so I think there's maybe
two trains of a thought on this topic
and it's worth experimenting with your
app to figure out what works best for
you guys I think one of the most
impactful things for fremium apps is to
understand what the fremium Bas is doing
for you are they seeing ads are they
sharing the app like is there a reason
for them to exist it like provides
business value and if not that's maybe
when you explore a hard pay wall one of
the things you were talking about too is
like how freemium can lead to this like
delusion looking at vanity metrics
versus like really understanding the
business there's some of these metrics
that you were talking about with
customer centered metrics like really
understanding the customer and the value
they're deriving from the app versus
these like big ma numbers but like
they're never going to pay you know a
certain number of people are never going
to pay Babel only deals with the people
who are actually paying so you
understand your customer base in a
really different way so you could you
talk to that for a sec it's probably
pretty funny but I couldn't tell you
what our daily active user number is or
our monthly active user number because
it's not what drives our growth model
right know we are a mission driven
company we are here to help people learn
languages and that's what our customers
goals are to their customers goal is not
to open an app every single day or every
single month like maybe that's what
helps them get to their goal but we are
very focused on helping our users
achieve their goal which is to learn a
language and so at Babel we do have a
proprietary metric that we optimize for
it's called learner success we've
invented it I think it's worth every app
and every company coming up with their
own metrics whether you know it's
something that aligns with what your
customer's actual objective is if you're
a company that's optimizing for a metric
that's not in your customer's best
interest you're probably not going to
end up in a really good place at the end
of the day and I found that a little bit
with many apps which is like you just
immediately assume it's daily active
users and monthly active users and
that's the number we need to optimize
for it's very easy to fall into that
trap but it might not be in best
interest of your customer if you're
looking at that so that's how we think
about it yeah and how do you think about
the impact of that on retention and like
kind of having money on the line and the
investment people make well I mean I
think if you are meeting your customers
goals then you're in a pretty good place
to keep them around for a lot longer and
so like having those checkpoints with
the customers so that they know that
they're actually on track that helps us
we're not sharing you know how many
daily active users or how many times
you've used the app with our users
because again it's not what their
objective is you mentioned having money
on the line you know when yeah there is
something to that when you're paying for
an app already that you're going to
stick with it a little bit more because
you you're paying for it you know there
is a little bit difference between a
free app and a paid app so we see that a
little bit I think we definitely see
like the people that are committing to
our most premium subscription offerings
like they're sticking around for a lot
longer mostly because they there's money
on the line yeah um it drives that
motivation money's a a good driver of
motivation so yeah that's that's a
little bit of what we've seen awesome so
last topic as we're wrapping up I know
you know babbles had the web product for
a long time and optimized for web for a
long time but it's kind of a really hot
topic in the industry right now of web
to app driving people to the web I know
a lot of your advertising goes web first
you know people really struggle to crack
that flow any top tips for apps
struggling to make web to app work yeah
I mean I think this gets back into the
the original conversation around around
offline channels and where people are
where they are and where they come from
you know we've designed both an app flow
for our users as well as a web flow
because we found that different people
go to different places with our offline
channels it's kind of interesting if
someone sees a TV ad it's a 50/50 chance
that they're going to visit you on your
app or on the web we can't figure out
how to change that it's hit or miss so
yeah we've we've optimized both for the
App Stores and the app experience as
well for a web experience there's
honestly not a lot of difference between
them most of the time people are coming
on their phones anyway there's only a
very slight difference between like
being on your phone and going through a
website and being on the phone and going
through an app I think the difference we
have and why we optimize a lot for the
web is you don't have that upfront
download blackbox exactly we have a lot
better data on web you know and just
getting someone to download is a big
step and to not have any touch points
with your customer I talked about the
discovery stage like we do the discovery
stage on web immediately
there's no commitment from the user at
that point all they've done is visited
the website and now we're talking to
them through this kind of quiz like
survey experience and understanding what
their needs are collecting data on them
as well whereas on the app experience
it's like it takes a big hurdle for them
to download the app but they haven't had
a conversation with you yet so there's a
few reasons why we want to optimize for
web it's we get better data and we can
have a deeper conversation and a better
discoverability stage with them but also
just because they're going there and we
can't control that so yeah there is if
you are going to get into the offline
space you're going to want to design an
a web experience yeah yeah all right
well thank you so much for sharing all
these great insights you know if if
you're an app and haven't considered
offline ads or just being more creative
about your marketing strategy like
there's just so many ways to get
people's attention think Beyond those
just kind of standard channels that
everybody's talking about because there
just are so many opportunities to be
more creative with marketing and Babel's
been making it work for a long time and
doing some really creative stuff so like
get out of that little box I will add
I'm not a traditional offline marketer I
think five years ago if you asked me
that I'd be talking about offline
marketing on a podcast or on stage I
would have laughed at you like my I'm a
digital marketer background so it's not
too late to get into this you can learn
and yeah it's definitely something I
think every company should explore yeah
anything else you wanted to as we wrap
up not too much it's it's great to be
here thanks for having me if you guys
are interested in learning a language Go
download Babble or go to our our website
and or even just just follow us in in
terms of all the marketing and growth
related things that we're doing so
thanks thanks so much for listening if
you have a minute please leave a review
in your favorite podcast player you can
also stop by chat. sub club.com to join
our private community yeah
[Music]